Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're going to a very special place, Marco, a place where
我是Catherine，今天我们要去一个非常特别的地方，Marco，一个
men and women alike, but usually women are associated with it.
男女都爱去，但通常和女性联系在一起的地方。
And where these women like to go.
这些女性喜欢去的地方。
What is this place we're going to?
我们要去的是哪里呢？
That's right.
没错。
Today we are going to a beauty spa.
今天我们要去一个美容水疗中心。
All right.
好的。
So let's check that out in today's vocabulary preview.
那么，让我们在今天的词汇预览中看看。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So this place, a beauty spa, it's interesting because it's not just a normal spa.
这个地方，美容水疗中心，很有趣，因为它不只是普通的水疗中心。
It's a particular spa where you get treated for some things.
它是一个特别的水疗中心，你可以在这里接受一些护理。
That's right.
没错。
So a beauty spa is a place where you go to feel good.
所以美容水疗中心是一个让你感觉良好的地方。
So women and men like to have their nails and their faces and their skin taken care
所以女性和男性都喜欢在这里护理指甲、面部和皮肤，
of.
得到照顾。
Maybe their makeup and hair as well.
可能还有化妆和头发。
So it's not just a place where you maybe go for a massage, but you get a lot of other
所以它不仅仅是一个你可能去做按摩的地方，你还能得到很多其他
services that make your skin nice, make you look and feel good.
服务，让你的皮肤变好，让你看起来和感觉都很好。
All right.
好的。
So that's where we're going today.
这就是我们今天要去的地方。
So beauty spa, and we're going to talk about all the different things that you can do there.
所以美容水疗中心，我们要聊聊在那里可以做的各种事情。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the very first time.
那么，让我们第一次听一下对话。
You want to go get a facial with me today?
你今天想和我一起去做面部护理吗？
Dude, what are you talking about?
哥们，你在说什么？
Only girls do that.
只有女生才做那个。
Not at all.
才不是呢。
Guys also get facials, manicures and pedicures.
男生也做面部护理、美甲和足部护理。
There's nothing wrong with looking after your skin and looking good.
照顾皮肤和保持好看没什么不对的。
True.
确实。
So what do they do to you at your beauty spa?
那在你的美容水疗中心，他们对你做什么？
Well, first they exfoliate my face, getting rid of all the dead skin.
嗯，首先他们给我的脸去角质，去除所有死皮。
Then I get a face mask with nutrients that keep my skin healthy and young.
然后我敷一个面膜，含有营养，让我的皮肤健康年轻。
Afterwards, they apply some moisturizer and you leave feeling like a million bucks.
之后，他们涂上一些保湿霜，你离开时感觉棒极了。
That doesn't really sound like something I would be interested in.
听起来真不像我会感兴趣的事。
In any case, I just wash my face every night and use sunscreen during the day.
不管怎样，我只是每晚洗脸，白天用防晒霜。
Well, you should come with me one day.
嗯，你应该哪天跟我一起去。
I'm sure you'll love it.
我相信你会喜欢的。
Uh, no.
呃，不要。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at language takeaway.
那么现在让我们看看语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Got a lot of great phrases and words in language takeaway today.
今天的语言要点里有很多好短语和单词。
The first one though is from the very first line of dialogue.
第一个来自对话的第一行。
You want to go get a facial with me today?
你今天想和我一起去做面部护理吗？
That's right.
没错。
We are asking our friend if he wants to go with us to go get a facial.
我们在问朋友是否想和我们一起去做面部护理。
Now what exactly does it mean to get a facial?
那么做面部护理到底是什么意思呢？
All right, a facial here is a thing, in this case, a service that we would pay for.
好的，这里的面部护理是一个东西，在这种情况下，是一种我们要付费的服务。
And basically a facial is just a skincare treatment or a treatment for your face.
基本上，面部护理就是一种护肤护理或面部护理。
So maybe you'll get some cream and cleansing and, uh, you know, in the advertisements you
所以你可能得到一些面霜和清洁，呃，你知道，在广告里
often see someone getting a facial with like cucumbers on their eyes.
你经常看到有人做面部护理，眼睛上放着黄瓜片。
And so it's just a way to make your skin feel really good.
所以这只是让皮肤感觉很好的方法。
Okay.
好的。
Particularly on your face.
特别是针对你的脸。
Yes.
是的。
Your face.
你的脸。
And the verb here is to get.
这里的动词是“做”。
So I'm going to get a facial or I got a facial yesterday.
所以我要去做面部护理，或者我昨天做了面部护理。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
Now, um, we, apart from getting a facial, getting a special treatment on your face,
现在，嗯，除了做面部护理，做面部特殊护理，
you can also get a manicure and a pedicure.
你还可以做美甲和足部护理。
That's right.
没错。
So manicure, pedicure, these we're going to keep together because they're very similar,
所以美甲、足部护理，我们把它们放在一起，因为它们很相似，
but they're a little bit different.
但有点不同。
Manny, manicure, Manny, that means something to do with the hands.
Manny，美甲，Manny，意思是和手有关。
So manicure is actually when you have your fingernails kind of cleaned and taken care
所以美甲实际上是指你的手指甲被清洁和护理，
of and then they will apply some paint.
然后他们会涂上一些颜料。
So nail polish.
也就是指甲油。
So basically having your nails treated and then colored.
所以基本上就是护理指甲然后上色。
Okay.
好的。
And then pedicure I imagine is the same thing, but for your feet.
然后足部护理，我猜是同样的事情，但针对脚。
That's right.
没错。
Pedi refers to feet.
Pedi指的是脚。
So pedicure is the same treatment, the same service, but for your toes.
所以足部护理是同样的护理，同样的服务，但针对脚趾。
And in this case you'd have very, you know, nice nail polish on your toes.
在这种情况下，你的脚趾上会有很漂亮的指甲油。
All right.
好的。
Now, going back to skin treatment, because well, manicure and pedicure for your fingernails
现在，回到皮肤护理的话题，因为，嗯，美甲和足部护理是针对你的手指甲
and for your hands and feet, we are talking about getting your face exfoliated or he says,
以及你的手和脚，我们讨论的是给脸部去角质，或者他说，
well, first they exfoliate my face.
嗯，首先他们给我的脸去角质。
So exfoliate, you think exfoliate means taking something away.
所以“去角质”，你会觉得去角质意味着去掉一些东西。
In this case to exfoliate means to take the dead skin away.
在这种情况下，去角质意味着去除死皮。
And sometimes this can be a little bit painful because you think at first you have some dry
有时候这可能会有点疼，因为你一开始觉得有一些干燥的
skin, some dead skin, they have to take it away.
皮肤、一些死皮，他们必须把它去掉。
They have to use something rough.
他们得用一些粗糙的东西。
You can do it on your feet as well.
你也可以在脚上做这个。
But when they exfoliate your face, they use some kind of cleanser or some kind of maybe
但当他们给你的脸去角质时，他们会用某种洁面产品或某种可能
sponge to clear the dead skin.
是海绵来清除死皮。
And then afterwards you have the fresh new skin and it's very smooth and nice looking.
然后之后你就会有新鲜的新皮肤，非常光滑好看。
Okay.
好的。
So that's what it means to exfoliate the skin.
所以这就是给皮肤去角质的意思。
It can be on your face, your feet, pretty much anywhere in your body.
可以在你的脸上、脚上，几乎身体任何部位。
And lastly, we also are just using sunscreen during the day to protect our skin and to
最后，我们白天也会使用防晒霜来保护皮肤，
keep it healthy.
保持健康。
That's right.
没错。
So sunscreen is a kind of cream.
所以防晒霜是一种乳霜。
Do you use sunscreen, Marco?
你涂防晒霜了吗，Marco？
No.
不。
No, you don't have to.
不，你不需要。
No, never.
不，从来没有。
Well, I often use sunscreen because I'm very, very pale.
嗯，我经常涂防晒霜，因为我皮肤非常非常白。
And so when I go in the sun, maybe at the beach, it's very easy for me to burn my skin
所以当我在阳光下，比如在海滩上，很容易就会晒伤皮肤。
to turn red.
变成红色。
And so sunscreen helps me protect my skin.
所以防晒霜能帮我保护皮肤。
So that's exactly what it does.
所以它就是这么用的。
Sunscreen is a specific type of lotion that you put on your skin and it prevents you from
防晒霜是一种特殊的乳液，涂抹在皮肤上可以防止你被晒伤。
getting sunburns or from darkening your skin.
晒伤或者让皮肤变黑。
That's right.
没错。
So those are the words we have relating to skincare and some of these services at the
这些就是我们关于护肤以及部分相关服务的词汇。
beauty spa.
美容水疗。
But we've got some more phrases for you.
但我们还为你准备了一些短语。
So let's first listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a moment.
那么我们先再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
You want to go get a facial with me today?
你今天想跟我一起去做个面部护理吗？
Dude, what are you talking about?
老兄，你在说什么呢？
Only girls do that.
只有女孩子才会那样做。
Not at all.
不客气。
Guys also get facials, manicures and pedicures.
男生也会做面部护理、修指甲和修脚。
There's nothing wrong with looking after your skin and looking good.
照顾好自己的皮肤、保持好看没什么不对。
True.
没错。
So what should they do to you at your beauty spa?
那在美容水疗中心，他们会给你做什么呢？
Well, first they exfoliate my face, getting rid of all the dead skin.
嗯，首先他们会给我的脸去角质，去除所有死皮。
Then I get a face mask with nutrients that keep my skin healthy and young.
然后我会敷一个含有营养的面膜，让我的皮肤保持健康和年轻。
Afterwards, they apply some moisturizer and you leave feeling like a million bucks.
之后，他们会涂上一些保湿霜，你离开时感觉棒极了。
That doesn't really sound like something I would be interested in.
听起来真不像我会感兴趣的事。
In any case, I just wash my face every night and use sunscreen during the day.
不管怎样，我每天晚上只洗脸，白天涂防晒霜。
Well, you should come with me one day.
嗯，你改天应该跟我一起去。
I'm sure you'll love it.
我肯定你会喜欢的。
Uh, no.
呃，不要。
All right.
好吧。
So now it's time for some fluency builder.
那么现在是流利表达时间。
Let's check out three key phrases.
我们来看看三个关键短语。
Fluency builder.
流利表达。
So we've got this first phrase here, not at all.
我们这里有第一个短语，“一点也不”。
So one person says only girls go to the beauty spa and what does the other person say?
所以一个人说只有女生去美容水疗中心，另一个人会说什么？
Right?
对吧？
He says, no, not at all.
他说，“不，一点也不。”
Not at all.
一点也不。
So basically he's responding by saying, no, that's not true.
所以基本上他是在回应说，不，那不是真的。
Now you could have said no, but why do you say not at all?
你本可以说“不”，但为什么你要说“一点也不”呢？
You can say no, but no is almost rude.
你可以说“不”，但“不”几乎有点粗鲁。
Not at all is a way to say, actually in reality, this is different.
“一点也不”是一种表达方式，意思是实际上，事实并非如此。
So it's a, it's a more polite way of disagreeing with what the person just said.
所以这是一种更礼貌的方式，用来反驳对方刚才说的话。
Okay.
好的。
So you can say no, not at all.
所以你可以说“不，一点也不”。
I guess you can say both, right?
我想你可以两个一起说，对吧？
Not at all or together.
“一点也不”或者连在一起说。
No, not at all.
不，一点也不。
You could say, um, women don't like to watch football and you can say, oh, not at all.
你可以说，嗯，女人不喜欢看足球，然后你可以说，哦，一点也不。
You could say only men like to watch football.
你可以说只有男人喜欢看足球。
Right?
对吧？
And then if I disagree or you say, actually, I can say, no, not at all.
然后如果我不同意，或者你说实际上，我可以说，不，一点也不。
Actually girls like to watch football as well.
实际上女孩也喜欢看足球。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So now continuing on with the skincare topic, we saw this interesting verb, to apply some
那么继续护肤话题，我们看到了这个有趣的动词，“涂抹一些”。
moisturizer.
保湿霜。
So the verb here is to apply something on your skin.
所以这里的动词是“涂抹”在皮肤上。
All right.
好的。
So the verb to apply means to put on, okay.
所以动词“涂抹”意思是“涂上”，明白吗。
Or to use.
或者“使用”。
And this is a verb we often use with beauty care products, like apply the shampoo to your
这是一个我们经常用在美容护理产品上的动词，比如把洗发水涂在
head or apply some fingernail polish.
头上，或者涂指甲油。
Means that you're going to, yeah, to put it on yourself.
意思是你要，嗯，把它涂在自己身上。
Right.
对。
So when we say apply some moisturizer is to use moisturizer.
所以当我们说“涂抹保湿霜”就是使用保湿霜。
Yeah, to put it on your skin.
是的，把它涂在皮肤上。
Like I apply my makeup, that means I put the makeup on my skin.
就像我化妆，意思是我把化妆品涂在皮肤上。
So in this case, moisturizer is a great cream that we use when our skin is dry and we want
所以在这种情况下，保湿霜是一种很好的面霜，当我们的皮肤干燥时使用，我们想让
it to be more healthy.
它更健康。
We want it to be less dry and we add this.
我们想让它不那么干，然后我们加上这个。
Okay.
好的。
And lastly, after you exfoliate, you apply moisturizer, you do everything.
最后，去角质后，你涂保湿霜，做所有步骤。
He says that you leave the beauty salon feeling like a million bucks.
他说你离开美容院时感觉像百万富翁一样。
All right.
好的。
To feel like a million bucks.
感觉像百万富翁一样。
This is a phrase that we often use to say you feel wonderful.
这是一个我们常用来表达感觉极好的短语。
Feel great.
感觉棒极了。
You feel really good.
你感觉非常好。
And so this is the main reason to go to the beauty spa, right Marco?
所以这就是去美容水疗的主要原因，对吧，Marco？
Right.
没错。
So you go there because you want to feel like a million bucks.
所以你去那里是因为你想感觉像百万富翁一样棒。
So you feel very, very, very good.
所以你感觉非常、非常、非常好。
Sometimes when I buy a new outfit and I try it on, I'm really excited.
有时候我买新衣服试穿时，会特别兴奋。
I say, Oh, I feel like a million bucks.
我会说，哦，我感觉棒极了。
So I guess the other form of this word will actually be, you look like a million bucks.
所以我想这个词的另一种形式其实是，你看起来棒极了。
Someone can look like a million bucks.
有人可以看起来像百万富翁一样棒。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So I see my friend coming from the beauty spa and I say, wow, you look like a million
所以当我看到朋友从美容水疗出来时，我会说，哇，你看起来棒极了。
bucks.
棒极了。
You look great.
你看起来很棒。
All right.
好的。
So let's listen to our dialogue one last time.
那么让我们最后听一遍对话。
Let's review everything and we'll be back in a bit.
我们来回顾一下所有内容，一会儿就回来。
You want to go get a facial with me today?
你今天想跟我一起去做面部护理吗？
Dude, what are you talking about?
老兄，你在说什么呢？
Only girls do that.
只有女孩子才那样做。
Not at all.
才不是呢。
Guys also get facials, manicures and pedicures.
男生也会做面部护理、修指甲和修脚。
There's nothing wrong with looking after your skin and looking good.
照顾皮肤、让自己好看没什么不对。
True.
没错。
So what should they do to you at your beauty spa?
那他们会在你的美容水疗中心给你做什么呢？
Well, first they exfoliate my face, getting rid of all the dead skin.
嗯，首先他们会给我去角质，去掉所有死皮。
Then I get a face mask with nutrients that keep my skin healthy and young.
然后我会敷一个含有营养的面膜，让皮肤保持健康年轻。
Afterwards, they apply some moisturizer and you leave feeling like a million bucks.
之后，他们会涂上保湿霜，你离开时感觉棒极了。
That doesn't really sound like something I would be interested in.
听起来真不像我会感兴趣的事。
In any case, I just wash my face every night and use sunscreen during the day.
反正，我每晚只洗脸，白天涂防晒霜。
Well, you should come with me one day.
嗯，你改天应该跟我一起去。
I'm sure you'll love it.
我保证你会喜欢的。
Uh, no.
呃，不要。
All right.
好吧。
So facials, this sort of thing is commonly mostly associated with women.
所以面部护理这类事情通常主要和女性联系在一起。
But as we saw in the dialogue, more and more men are actually taking care of their skin
但正如我们在对话中看到的，越来越多的男性实际上在照顾自己的皮肤
and their appearance.
和外表。
That's right.
没错。
This might have been traditionally a woman's event, going to the spa, having a girl's day
这传统上可能是女性的活动，去水疗中心，过个女孩日。
at the spa.
在水疗中心。
You're right, Marco.
你说得对，马可。
A lot of men like to do this.
很多男人也喜欢做这个。
Just because you get a manicure doesn't mean you have to have pink fingernails.
做美甲不代表你非得涂粉色指甲油。
You can actually just have your nails taken care of and cleaned and cut and your cuticles
你其实只是让指甲得到护理、清洁、修剪，还有你的指甲边缘
taken care of.
得到护理。
So it feels really nice.
所以感觉真的很舒服。
That's right.
没错。
Actually, it's a common new trend that we've even heard in the news about.
实际上，这是一个常见的新趋势，我们甚至在新闻里听说过。
And the term that men are labeled with when they take excessive care of their skin and
当男人过度护理自己的皮肤和
their appearance, they say they're metrosexuals.
外表时，他们被贴上的标签是“都市型男”。
Metrosexual.
都市型男。
Right.
对。
Now, this is a man who, like you say, likes to dress nicely, takes care of his hair, has
这种人，就像你说的，喜欢穿得得体，打理头发，
nice skin, someone who really takes care of their body.
皮肤好，真正注重保养身体。
And it's different from being a homosexual, for example, where maybe that's a stereotype
这和同性恋不同，比如我们可能有一种刻板印象，
that we have, where we say, oh, well, some people who are homosexual like to dress very
认为有些同性恋喜欢穿得很
well and take care of their skin.
好并护理皮肤。
Metrosexual people, men, are straight.
都市型男，这些男人，是异性恋。
They're not gay.
他们不是同性恋。
But they still like to do these things, to go to the spa or to take care of their appearances.
但他们仍然喜欢做这些事情，比如去水疗中心或打理自己的外表。
Right.
没错。
So it's a very interesting topic, specifically nowadays, where this type of thing is more
所以这是一个非常有趣的话题，尤其是在当今，这类事情越来越
and more common.
普遍。
And yet still in many places and cultures, it's very much taboo.
然而在许多地方和文化中，这仍然是非常忌讳的。
Obviously, being manly man associated with that is, you know, you don't really take care
显然，那种“硬汉”形象与之相关的是，你知道，你并不会真正打理
of your appearance.
自己的外表。
You know, you wake up and you still look kind of messy and half asleep or, you know, guy
你知道，你醒来时看起来还是有点邋遢、半睡半醒，或者，你知道，男人
has scars and beards and stuff.
有伤疤、胡须之类的东西。
So you don't really associate it much.
所以你不会把两者联系起来。
But it's very interesting to see these types of different cultural aspects.
但看到这些不同类型的文化方面非常有趣。
So we would like to know if in your culture, your country, this is a common practice.
所以我们想知道，在你的文化、你的国家，这是否是一种常见的做法。
Is it acceptable or is it very, very rare?
它是可以接受的，还是非常非常罕见？
And if you go to the beauty spa, whether you're a man or a woman, what's your favorite service?
如果你去美容水疗中心，无论你是男性还是女性，你最喜欢的服务是什么？
Do you like the facials?
你喜欢面部护理吗？
Do you like the pedicures?
你喜欢足部护理吗？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye.
再见。